A Guide to the Norman Sisisky Papers, 1982-2001
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Project Files, 1982-2001., Extent: 26 boxes. (Box 28-53)
  - Norfolk Harbor Operation and Maintenance Project. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Norfolk State Modeling, Analysis and Simulation Center. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Nottoway County Agricultural Export Center. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Nottoway County Agricultural Export Facility. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Nottoway County Courthouse Renovation Project. (Box 44, Folder 3-4)
  - Nottoway County Schools. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Nottoway Falls Project. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Nuclear Physics. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - ODU Center for Advanced Ship Repair and Maintenance. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - ODU - Military Conversion. (Box 44, Folder 9-10)
  - Olde Petersburg Home for Men. (Box 41, Folder 11-12)
  - Pagan River. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - "Path of Glory" Project - Portsmouth. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Petersburg Community Development Block Grant. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Petersburg Lead-Based Paint Hazard Control Grant. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Petersburg National Battlefield. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Petersburg Penitentiary. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Petersburg Tornado, 1993. (Box 45, Folder 5-9)
  - Pinners Point Connector. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Portsmouth Drug Court Planning Grant. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Portsmouth HOPE VI Grant. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Portsmouth Magnet School. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Prescription Drug Pricing Study. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Prescription Drug Pricing Survey. (Box 46, Folder 1-5)
  - "Project Impact" - Chesapeake. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Public Defender's Office. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Ramsey Iron. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Rawls Apartment Complex - Suffolk. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Regional Law Enforcement Information Sharing System. (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Relay for Life. (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Resident Opportunities and Self Sufficiency Program - Suffolk. (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Ricky Ray Hemophilia Relief Fund. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Route 17. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Route 104/Dominion Boulevard. (Box 47, Folder 2-4)
  - Route 168 - Battlefield Boulevard. (Box 41, Folder 5-12)
  - Route 168 - Chesapeake Expressway. (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Route 288 - Richmond. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Smithfield Foods. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Sound Barrier - Route 164. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - South Battlefield Boulevard/State Route 168, Chesapeake - Project Criteria. (Box 48, Folder 6-7)
  - South Battlefield Boulevard/State Route 168, Chesapeake - Investment Criteria. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Southside Planning District. (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Southside Virginia Community College. (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Southside Virginia Community College - Student Support Services Grant Appeal. (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Southside Virginia Community College Welfare to Work Grant. (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Stringfield, John A. - Pocahontas Neighborhood. (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Suffolk Landfill. (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
  - Suffolk Redevelopment and Housing Authority. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Suffolk Redevelopment and Housing Authority - Welfare to Work Grant. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - TBT Treatment Plant for Shipyard Wastewater. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Technology Reinvestment Project. (Box 49, Folder 6-10)
  - Third Crossing of Hampton Roads. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Tidewater Community College. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Trans-Super Airports. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Transportation. (Box 50, Folder 4-9)
  - Transportation - UMTA Section 3 Grant Request. (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Tyler's Beach. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - United Airlines MOC II - Dulles. (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - USDA/1890 Initiative. (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - VCU Great Cities Universities Community Development Partnership. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Alliance for Manufacturing Competitiveness. (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Cardiac Surgery Initiative. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Center for Sustainable Health Access. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Gateway 21. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Historical Society - Custis Family Papers. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Housing. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Power - Dry Casks. (Box 51, Folder 8-9)
  - Virginia Regional Technology Alliance - Night Vision Products. (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Sports Hall of Fame. (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - VSU Comprehensive Health Career Opportunities Program. (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - VSU Gospel Chorale - Kennedy Center State Days. (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - VUU Appropriations. (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Union/HUD. (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Writing Project. (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Washington Park. (Box 51, Folder 17-18)
  - Washington Park. (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
  - Wetland Regulations (Bazzanella). (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Wetlands. (Box 52, Folder 4-10)
  - Wetlands. (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Youth Leadership Initiative. (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Series III. Computer Letter Texts, 1983-1996., Extent: 6 boxes. (Box 54-59)
  The computer letter texts are drafts and final versions of form letters sent to constituents on specific legislation or issues. Some have approval sheets attached requesting review by Sisisky or senior staff. Various coding systems were used. Two have prefixes PF and GG (iinitials for two members of Sisisky's staff), followed by consecutive numbers. There is also a group numbered from 18000 to 30015, a series numbered A1-A22221 which includes a partial key, and finally a group with the letter notations AGBIL-WEREF, which includes a complete key.
  Numerical
  - PF1 - PF50. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - PF51 - PF100. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - PF101 - PF150. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - PF151 - PF200. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - PF201 - PF250. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - PF251 - PF300. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - PF301 - PF350. (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - PF351 - PF399. (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - PF400 - PF450. (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - PF451 - PF500. (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - PF501 - PF550. (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - PF551 - PF600. (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - PF601 - PF650. (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - PF651 - PF700. (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - PF701 - PF750. (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - PF751 - PF800. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - PF801 - PF850. (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - PF851 - PF900. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - PF901 - PF950. (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - PF951 - PF1000. (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - GG425 - GG475. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - GG476 - GG525. (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - GG526 - GG580. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - GG581 - GG625. (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - GG626 - GG675. (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - GG676 - GG736. (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - GG737 - GG775. (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - GG776 - GG825. (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - GG826 - GG875. (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - GG876 - GG925. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - GG926 - GG975. (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - GG976 - GG1037. (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - GG1038 - GG1075. (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - GG1076 - GG1125. (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - GG1126 - GG1175. (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - GG1176 - GG1225. (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - GG1226 - GG1275. (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - GG1276 - GG1325. (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - GG1326 - GG1375. (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - GG1376 - GG1413. (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Sample Letters. (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - 18000 - 22025. (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - 22041 - 22210. (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - 22222 - 22999. (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - 23000 - 27500. (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - 27506 - 29323. (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - 29324 - 29564. (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - 29565 - 30015. (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - 1 - 1600. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - 1601 - 4999. (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - 5000 - 119999. (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - 12000 - 12100. (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - 12101 - 13020. (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - 13021 - 14050. (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - 14250 - 15200. (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - 15201 - 15410. (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - 15411 - 15599. (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - 15600 - 15906. (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - 16000 - 16070. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - 16074 - 16269. (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - 16270 - 17000. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - 17001 - 17600. (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - 17605 - 22000. (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - 22021 - 22117. (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - 22120 - 22221. (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Interest Code Master File. (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - AGBIL - CRGUN. (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - CRPRV - ENWST. (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - FAAID - ITMEX. (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - JUABO - LASTD. (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - LATRN - WEREF. (Box 59, Folder 13)
- Series IV. Press Clippings, 1982-1995., Extent: 14 boxes. (Box 60-73)
  The press clippings cover the period from December 1982 to December 1995, and are arranged chronologically. There are a few articles from 1996 to 2001. This series contains photocopies of articles on Sisisky and other members of the Virginia congressional delegation, and other stories of local or national interest. They are mainly from Virginia newspapers, but there are some from national publications as well. There are typed listings of each clipping at the beginning of each month for the years 1984 and 1985.
  Chronological
  - December 1982. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - January 1983. (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - February 1983. (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - March 1983. (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - April 1983. (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - May 1983. (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - June 1983. (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - July 1983. (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - August 1983. (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - September 1983. (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - October 1983. (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - November 1983. (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - December 1983. (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - January 1984. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - February 1984. (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - March 1984. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - April 1984. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - May 1984. (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - June 1984. (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - July 1984. (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - August 1984. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - September 1984. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - October 1984. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - November 1984. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - December 1984. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - January 1985. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - February 1985. (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - March 1985. (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - April 1985. (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - May 1985. (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - June 1985. (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - July 1985. (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - August 1985. (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - September 1985. (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - October 1985. (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - November 1985. (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - December 1985. (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - January 1986. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - February 1986. (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - March 1986. (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - April 1986. (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - May 1986. (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - June 1986. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - July 1986. (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - August 1986. (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - September 1986. (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - October 1986. (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - November 1986. (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - December 1986. (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - January 1987. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - February 1987. (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - March 1987. (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - April 1987. (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - May 1987. (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - June 1987. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - July 1987. (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - August 1987. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - September 1987. (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - October 1987. (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - November 1987. (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - December 1987. (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - January 1988. (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - February 1988. (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - March 1988. (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - April 1988. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - May 1988. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - June 1988. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - July 1988. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - August 1988. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - September 1988. (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - October 1988. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - November 1988. (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - December 1988. (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - January 1989. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - February 1989. (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - March 1989. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - April 1989. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - May 1989. (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - June 1989. (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - July 1989. (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - August 1989. (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - September 1989. (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - October 1989. (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - November 1989. (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - December 1989. (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - January 1990. (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - February 1990. (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - March 1990. (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - May 1990. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - June 1990. (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - July 1990. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - August 1990. (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - September 1990. (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - October 1990. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - November 1990. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - December 1990. (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - January 1991. (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - February 1991. (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - March 1991. (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - April 1991. (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - May 1991. (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - June 1991. (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - July 1991. (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - August 1991. (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - September 1991. (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - October 1991. (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - November 1991. (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - December 1991. (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - January 1992. (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - February 1992. (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - March 1992. (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - April 1992. (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - May 1992. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - June 1992. (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - July 1992. (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - August 1992. (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - September 1992. (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - October 1992. (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - November 1992. (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - December 1992. (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - January 1993. (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - February 1993. (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - March 1993. (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - April 1993. (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - May 1993. (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - June 1993. (Box 70, Folder 3-4)
  - July 1993. (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - August 1993. (Box 70, Folder 6-7)
  - September 1993. (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - October 1993. (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - November 1993. (Box 70, Folder 10-11)
  - December 1993. (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - January 1994. (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - February 1994. (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - March 1994. (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - April 1994. (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - May 1994. (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - June 1994. (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - July 1994. (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - August 1994. (Box 71, Folder 8-9)
  - September 1994. (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - October 1994. (Box 72, Folder 2-3)
  - November 1994. (Box 72, Folder 4-5)
  - December 1994. (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - January 1995. (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - February 1995. (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - March 1995. (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - April 1995. (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - May 1995. (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - June 1995. (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - July 1995. (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - August 1995. (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - September 1995. (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - October 1995. (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - November 1995. (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - December 1995. (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - 1996 - 2001. (Box 73, Folder 10)
- Series V. Press Releases, 1983-2001., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 74-76)
  The press releases contain statements by Sisisky on legislation or events of local or national importance. They are arranged chronologically. Many of the releases are announcements of grants to localities or organizations, upcoming mobile office schedules, and notifications of events where Sisisky would be appearing or speaking. There is a listing of releases issued for 1990 to 1995 at the beginning of each folder.
  - 1983 (January - June). (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - 1983 (July - December). (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - 1984 (January - June). (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - 1984 (July - December). (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - 1985. (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - 1986. (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - 1987. (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - 1988. (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - 1989 (January - June). (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - 1989 (July - December). (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - 1990 - 1991. (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - 1992 - 1993. (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - 1994 (January - May). (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - 1994 (June - August). (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - 1994 (September - December). (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - 1995 (January - February). (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - 1995 (March - May). (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - 1995 (June - August). (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - 1995 (September - October). (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - 1995 (November - December). (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - 1996 (January - February). (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - 1996 (March - June). (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - 1996 (July - December). (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - 1997. (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - 1998. (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - 1999. (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - 2000. (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - 2001. (Box 76, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Speeches, 1983-2000., Extent: 14 boxes. (Box 77-90)
  The speeches contain copies of remarks delivered by Sisisky to various civic, religious, and cultural organizations, mostly in Virginia's Fourth Congressional district. There is also testimony by him before various House and Senate committees. There are copies of floor statements and testimonies for 1983 to 1987 at the end of the series. The arrangement of the speeches is chronological, but not strictly. For example, the speeches for 1994 are in reverse chronological order. There is a "speech index" that was prepared by Sisisky's staff at the beginning of each year, but not all of the speeches are included on the list. The researcher should consult the Library's finding aid for a complete listing. Most of the folders contain only copies of his remarks. There is very little supporting documentation, correspondence, research, drafts, notes, or invitations to the particular event.
  - Speech Index, 1983. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Pearl Harbor (1983). (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Southern Legislators Conference, Williamsburg - 13 December 1983. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Petersburg Area Clergy - 28 November 1983. (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Waters Junior High Honor Society Inductees - 23 November 1983. (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Petersburg Chamber of Commerce - 9 November 1983. (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Holy Angels Catholic Church - 11 September 1983. (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Retirement Speech (1983). (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Central Civic Forum, Portsmouth - 23 November 1983. (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - West Munden Civic League - 15 December 1983. (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Export Conference (1983). (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Counseling Services Facility Dedication (1983). (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Chesapeake Men for Progress - 10 June 1983. (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - 75th Anniversary Synagogue (1983). (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Colonel Mayes Fundraiser (1983). (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Welcome the USS Portsmouth (1983). (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Hopewell/Prince George Chamber of Commerce (1983). (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - Defense Issues (1983). (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - AFL-CIO (1983). (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Portsmouth Democratic Women - 13 August 1983. (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - Foster Grandparents (1983). (Box 77, Folder 21)
  - "Friends of Agriculture and Norman Sisisky" Dinner (1983). (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Western Tidewater Health Care Association - 13 May 1983. (Box 77, Folder 23)
  - Retired Officers Association (1983). (Box 77, Folder 24)
  - First Four Months (1983). (Box 77, Folder 25)
  - Coast Guard Cutter "Bear" (1983). (Box 77, Folder 26)
  - Small Business (1983). (Box 77, Folder 27)
  - Colonel Mayes Fundraiser (1983). (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Review of First 3 Months (1983). (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - Association of the United States Army (1983). (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - Democratic Values (1983). (Box 77, Folder 30)
  - Cheseapeake Democratic Women - 1 October 1983. (Box 77, Folder 31)
  - Chesapeake Volunteers Banquet (1983). (Box 77, Folder 32)
  - Emporia Chamber of Commerce (1983). (Box 77, Folder 33)
  - Child Safety Seat Law (1983). (Box 77, Folder 34)
  - Metal Trades Council (1983). (Box 77, Folder 35)
  - Douglas MacArthur Award (1983). (Box 77, Folder 36)
  - Reserve Officers Association, Petersburg (1983). (Box 77, Folder 37)
  - 70001 4th Annual Open House, Petersburg - 19 January 1983. (Box 77, Folder 38)
  - Graduation (1983). (Box 77, Folder 39)
  - Great Bridge High School Dedication (1983). (Box 77, Folder 40)
  - National Defense and National Security (1983). (Box 77, Folder 41)
  - Why I'm a Democrat (1983). (Box 77, Folder 42)
  - Shenandoah Apple Blossom Festival (1983). (Box 77, Folder 43)
  - Telephone Communications (1983). (Box 77, Folder 44)
  - Social Security Disability Program, House Select Committee on Aging - 12 September 1983. (Box 77, Folder 45)
  - Social Security Disability Program (1983). (Box 77, Folder 46)
  - Soviet Jewry (1983). (Box 77, Folder 47)
  - Elderly Issues (1983). (Box 77, Folder 48)
  - Virginia Peanut Growers, Wakefield - 29 March 1983. (Box 77, Folder 49)
  - VFW Ladies Auxiliary (1983). (Box 77, Folder 50)
  - VFW Loyalty Day Parade (1983). (Box 77, Folder 51)
  - Petersburg Democratic Committee (1983). (Box 77, Folder 52)
  - Virginia Division for Children (1983). (Box 77, Folder 53)
  - Speech Index, 1984. (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Petersburg Federated Woman's Club - 3 January 1984. (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - American Association of University Women, Chesapeake Chapter - 17 January 1984. (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Telecommunications Speech - 11 February 1984. (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Hopewell/Prince George Chamber of Commerce - 6 March 1984. (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Nat Krumbein Testimonial - 10 March 1984. (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Dinwiddie County Ruritans - 15 March 1984. (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Petersburg Small Business Conference - 21 March 1984. (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Manufacturers Association, Richmond - 22 March 1984. (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - The Jewish Vote (1984). (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Re-Election Announcement - 31 March 1984. (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Metal Trades Council - 3 April 1984. (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Young Democrats - 13 April 1984. (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Petersburg Lions Club - 17 April 1984. (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Norcom High School Honor Society - 18 April 1984. (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - American Society of Military Comptrollers - 19 April 1984. (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Beet Sugar Institute - 2 May 1984. (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Chesterfield County Democratic Dinner - 7 May 1984. (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - National Police Week/Peace Officers Memorial Day - 13 May 1984. (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Women in Business Conference - 14 May 1984. (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Democratic Convention, Norfolk - 18 May 1984. (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Old Dominion Bar Association - 25 May 1984. (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Slo-Pitch Softball Hall of Fame Museum - 8 June 1984. (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Craddock High School Commencement - 8 June 1984. (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - American Legion - 10 June 1984. (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - Flag Day (1984). (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Southern Police Institute - 28 July 1984. (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - Wesley Community Center Fundraiser - 28 July 1984. (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - Minority Business Conference, Petersburg - 10 September 1984. (Box 78, Folder 29)
  - Senior Citizens Convention, Blackstone - 15 September 1984. (Box 78, Folder 30)
  - Jim Olin Fundraiser, Roanoke - 16 September 1984. (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Bottlers, Williamsburg - 17 September 1984. (Box 78, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Carpenters and Joiners Union Convention (1984). (Box 78, Folder 33)
  - Suffolk Women's Club - 23 October 1984. (Box 78, Folder 34)
  - Fourth District Voters League - 27 October 1984. (Box 78, Folder 35)
  - Surry Elementary School Dedication - 11 November 1984. (Box 78, Folder 36)
  - Virginia Road and Transportation Builders Association - 27 November 1984. (Box 78, Folder 37)
  - Foreign Policy/Defense (1984). (Box 78, Folder 38)
  - Rising Health Care Costs and Their Impact on the Elderly, House Select Committee on Aging, Petersburg - 20 January 1984. (Box 78, Folder 39)
  - Fort Pickett Brigade Complex Dedication - 10 June 1984. (Box 78, Folder 40)
  - Defense Spending and Federal Deficits (1984). (Box 78, Folder 41)
  - National Defense and National Security (1984). (Box 78, Folder 42)
  - National Federation of Retired Federal Employees (1984). (Box 78, Folder 43)
  - Beet Sugar Association (1984). (Box 78, Folder 44)
  - Reserve Officers Association, Petersburg - (1984). (Box 78, Folder 45)
  - Economic Development, Emporia (1984). (Box 78, Folder 46)